<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>skytree on Tokyo, endless city</title>
    <link>/tags/skytree/</link>
    <description>Recent content in skytree on Tokyo, endless city</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/tags/skytree/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tower To Tower</title>
      <link>/posts/tower-to-tower/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tower-to-tower/</guid>
      <description>Two of the most iconic sites in modern Tokyo linked by this line of sight. In normal times countless eyes on the viewing platforms of both towers cast gazes that cross over the buildings below as they wonder who is looking their way from the other Tower. This is a tiny area of the whole panorama visible from Tokyo Tower, and yet see what a variety of style and scale compete for ground.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue Horizons</title>
      <link>/posts/blue-horizons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/blue-horizons/</guid>
      <description>Looking south over Sumida and Koto wards from the Skytree on an almost cloudless April morning over countless homes and businesses all the way to the Tokyo Gate Bridge and Haneda Airport and the highrise cluster of Chuo City. It looks vast, and yet is still only a small slice of the whole of Tokyo.
Below, in the long thin Sumida River Park where I had just walked, are chaperoned tribes of colourfully hatted kindergarten classes playing, and old men quietly fishing in a fragment of an old canal.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Count the buildings</title>
      <link>/posts/count-the-buildings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/count-the-buildings/</guid>
      <description>The variety in size, design, colour, texture and function of buildings in Tokyo never ceases to amaze and fascinate me. Looking east from the superb vantage point of the Skytree out over Kyojima and Yahiro, I wonder how many buildings there are in this one small area of the city. I wonder if any two are the same. The windows are like stars in the sky or grains of sand on a beach - uncountable.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mukojima district</title>
      <link>/posts/mukojima-district/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/mukojima-district/</guid>
      <description>Mukojima is a shitamachi district, meaning that it is comprised lowrise buildings in a somewhat less affluent area. The nearby Skytree looks over it now, and is a great place to view the district from, especially on a brilliant sunny day like this was.
Remember you can right click on the image to access it full size - something I especially recommend for photographs like this one.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracks and Skytree</title>
      <link>/posts/tracks-and-skytree/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tracks-and-skytree/</guid>
      <description>The Skytree watches over vast tracts of Tokyo, much of which still has an older, smaller, more patinated atmosphere. Areas around train tracks especially have that feel. Looking across the Tobu-Kameido Line here in Oshiage is one such place. Though only taken a year or so back the red building opposite is now gone, soon to replaced with who knows what.
That is another constant in Tokyo: Change.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
