<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>node on Tokyo, endless city</title>
    <link>/categories/node/</link>
    <description>Recent content in node on Tokyo, endless city</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/categories/node/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Post Office Reflections</title>
      <link>/posts/postoffice_reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/postoffice_reflections/</guid>
      <description>Some may think concrete, steel and glass buildings a bit soulless. But they have different and often appealing moods depending on the season and time of day. Here, the Marunouchi Post Office building shows interesting reflections of the nearby buildings and lovely clear blue December afternoon sky.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urban Eels</title>
      <link>/posts/urban-eels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/urban-eels/</guid>
      <description>It might just be me, but these Shinkansen, seen in Tokyo Station from a viewpoint on the Post Office viewing deck, look like giant futuristic eels lurking in an urban coral reef.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towers of Glass</title>
      <link>/posts/towers-of-glass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/towers-of-glass/</guid>
      <description>Tokyo has many stunning towers of glass, and this one, the newish Kitte building on the south side of Marunouchi Plaza, is one of my favourites. Here looking especially beautiful against a clear blue winter sky.
The viewing platform from where this photograph was taken is the perfect location for looking out over the plaza and Tokyo Station too.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marunouchi Plaza</title>
      <link>/posts/marunouchi-plaza/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/marunouchi-plaza/</guid>
      <description>Marunouchi Plaza is one of my favourite public spaces in Tokyo. There is an endless variety of contrasting architectures to look at and explore, not to mention some very fine vantage points for viewing the surrounding area. From the new post office building (where this photograph was taken from) to the wonderful Tokyo Station and even looking down Gyoko-dori towards the Imperial Palace there is so much to see and explore from this space.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tokyo Station</title>
      <link>/posts/tokyo-station/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tokyo-station/</guid>
      <description>Tokyo Station is an immense building with an amazing history. Here is the south side of the station, and the central dome.
It sits astride a massively complex transit system nexus and a vast underground shopping mall. With trains and metros, taxis, busses and coaches it truely is a location where journeys begin, end and transition.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shibuya in the rain</title>
      <link>/posts/shibuya-in-the-rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/shibuya-in-the-rain/</guid>
      <description>The night time city is always aglow with its endless neon (or more likely LED) lights, but when it rains the streets are covered with rivers of reflected lights that are quite otherworldly. The Shibuya Scramble Crossing is always a special place to be, but at night in a quiet warm rain with my combini umbrella there are few other places I would rather be.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hachiko</title>
      <link>/posts/hachiko/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hachiko/</guid>
      <description>The statue of the loyal dog, Hachiko, is probably the busiest meeting place in Tokyo. Outside Shibuya Station and next to the Scramble Crossing it is almost always heaving with locals waiting for friends and tourists posing for photos and touching his paw to ensure their wish to return to Tokyo is fulfilled.
This photograph was taken on a rare occasion when the area was fenced off for a ceremony.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
