<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>transport on Tokyo, endless city</title>
    <link>/tags/transport/</link>
    <description>Recent content in transport on Tokyo, endless city</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/tags/transport/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossings</title>
      <link>/posts/rail-crossing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/rail-crossing/</guid>
      <description>One of my favourite sounds in Tokyo is the sound of a level crossing. Just adjacent to Araiyakushi Mae station in the early morning people are making their way to work and school across the tracks. Many have just alighted from the departing ever-punctual train. The trains in Tokyo really are a wonder. We had just finished a three train journey across Tokyo during a Friday morning rush hour, and despite the sheer number of people, it never felt overcrowded or uncomfortable</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urban Eels</title>
      <link>/posts/urban-eels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/urban-eels/</guid>
      <description>It might just be me, but these Shinkansen, seen in Tokyo Station from a viewpoint on the Post Office viewing deck, look like giant futuristic eels lurking in an urban coral reef.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complex Road Junction</title>
      <link>/posts/complex-road-junction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/complex-road-junction/</guid>
      <description>Hakozaki Junction in Kakigaracho is typical of many such junctions in Tokyo. Multiple levels of overhead roads somehow weaving between hi-rise buildings, and barely noticeable from the streets below.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dawn over Nihonbashi Hakozaki-cho</title>
      <link>/posts/dawn-over-nihonbashihakozakicho/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/dawn-over-nihonbashihakozakicho/</guid>
      <description>There must be three dozen different buildings visible in this tiny sliver of Tokyo looking south west over Nihonbashi Hakozaki-cho. Each has its own architecture, scale and texture, standing on its own uniquely shaped plot of land. It was dawn on an April weekday when this was taken and most of these buildings were filling up with daily commuters as they began their working day.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracks and Skytree</title>
      <link>/posts/tracks-and-skytree/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tracks-and-skytree/</guid>
      <description>The Skytree watches over vast tracts of Tokyo, much of which still has an older, smaller, more patinated atmosphere. Areas around train tracks especially have that feel. Looking across the Tobu-Kameido Line here in Oshiage is one such place. Though only taken a year or so back the red building opposite is now gone, soon to replaced with who knows what.
That is another constant in Tokyo: Change.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
