<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>path on Tokyo, endless city</title>
    <link>/categories/path/</link>
    <description>Recent content in path on Tokyo, endless city</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/categories/path/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Under Marunouchi Plaza</title>
      <link>/posts/under_marunouchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/under_marunouchi/</guid>
      <description>There is a huge amount of pedestrian space underneath Tokyo, and often it can be pretty sparsely populated. This is from under Marunouchi Plaza near Tokyo Station taken early evening just before Christmas. These places provide access without consideration of traffic, and I think much of their reason for being were the number of pedestrian accidents. They also protect you from the elements whether that is rain, cold or heat, and are always well lit and very, very clean.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ningyocho Nights</title>
      <link>/posts/ningyocho-nights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ningyocho-nights/</guid>
      <description>This Chinese restaurant on a busy road looks and smells so inviting on a cool evening at the turn of the year. The whole road was lined with New Year lanterns at the time.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lucky Shutters</title>
      <link>/posts/luckyshutters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/luckyshutters/</guid>
      <description>The shutters drawn down over this tradional Japanese sweet shop depict the Seven Gods of Fortune that are said to bestow longevity, fortune, popularity, sincerity, kindness, dignity, and magnanimity.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossings</title>
      <link>/posts/rail-crossing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/rail-crossing/</guid>
      <description>One of my favourite sounds in Tokyo is the sound of a level crossing. Just adjacent to Araiyakushi Mae station in the early morning people are making their way to work and school across the tracks. Many have just alighted from the departing ever-punctual train. The trains in Tokyo really are a wonder. We had just finished a three train journey across Tokyo during a Friday morning rush hour, and despite the sheer number of people, it never felt overcrowded or uncomfortable</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utility Pole</title>
      <link>/posts/utility-pole/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/utility-pole/</guid>
      <description>Utility poles, with their spectacular nests of cables, are everywhere in Tokyo. They line the edges and paths of the city distributing power and communications to tens of millions of addresses. Some people find them ugly. More don&amp;rsquo;t even notice them, and on occasion the Government expresses its embarrassment at them. Personally I like them. It&amp;rsquo;s like looking up at vapour trails. It makes me wonder about the locations and people they connect.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cute Door</title>
      <link>/posts/cute_door/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/cute_door/</guid>
      <description>I am not enamoured of all things kawaii, but there is something intriguing about a door like this. One has to wonder what lies behind. Perhaps I have been watching too many Ghibli movies. This door was beside the Sumikko Gurashi store along 1st Avenue in the underground shopping mall of Tokyo Station on the Yaesu side.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ningyocho Night Bars</title>
      <link>/posts/ningyocho-nighttime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ningyocho-nighttime/</guid>
      <description>There is something wonderful about the bright neon lights and other signs that beckon you into darkened doorways on streets all around Tokyo. They often appear intimidating, especially for those without any Japanses language skills, but I have never had a bad experience and always found both the staff and clientel to be welcoming and friendly. This is a short stretch of a small street in Ningyocho.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunny Minato</title>
      <link>/posts/sunny_minato/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/sunny_minato/</guid>
      <description>It is interesting to see how many of the buildings around Tokyo Tower are not as tall as you might expect. Here, looking closer along Sakurada-dori south through Minato City towards Takanawa, the apartment and business buildings seem to rise as they get further away. It may not be deliberate, but it does have the happy consequence of making for many wonderful views from the Tower.
It was a lovely sunny day when I took this, making me want to join the pedestrians down on the sunlit pavement.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking down on Zojoji</title>
      <link>/posts/zojojitemple/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/zojojitemple/</guid>
      <description>The viewing platform at Tokyo Tower provides an excellent opportunity to look down on the magnificent Zojoji Temple complex. Taken at the end of 2020, and a few days before I was standing in the Temple on a subzero New Years Eve, this is a view from just before the world changed and the travel options we so much took for granted were taken away. The narrow road on the left is a familiar route for me, being my approach of choice to the iconic Tokyo Tower.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hato Bus</title>
      <link>/posts/hato-bus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hato-bus/</guid>
      <description>There is something special about a Japanese tour bus, and these from the 70 year old Hato Bus company, at the foot of Tokyo Tower, are a fine example. They carry you in comfort along the paths and between the districts of the city and beyond. The smartly uniformed staff keep you informed and entertained, and the views and sights are an endless source of opportunities to note for future exploration on foot.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roads and Skylines</title>
      <link>/posts/roads-and-skylines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/roads-and-skylines/</guid>
      <description>This photograph was taken looking south towards Shinkawa towards the end of the day. The red brickwork is part of the Royal Park Hotel.
I love the way layer upon layer of high rise buildings jostle for a place in the sky, presenting a line far more complex than the most intricate key, and just as unique. From every one of countless windows there is a different and individual skyline.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue Horizons</title>
      <link>/posts/blue-horizons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/blue-horizons/</guid>
      <description>Looking south over Sumida and Koto wards from the Skytree on an almost cloudless April morning over countless homes and businesses all the way to the Tokyo Gate Bridge and Haneda Airport and the highrise cluster of Chuo City. It looks vast, and yet is still only a small slice of the whole of Tokyo.
Below, in the long thin Sumida River Park where I had just walked, are chaperoned tribes of colourfully hatted kindergarten classes playing, and old men quietly fishing in a fragment of an old canal.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roads upon roads upon roads upon roads</title>
      <link>/posts/roads-upon-roads/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/roads-upon-roads/</guid>
      <description>The complexity of the transport infrastructure is not often appreciated from ground level, but at some places you can look up and see a glimpse of it. Like here at Hakozaki Junction where four layers of roads can be seen.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pink, white and blue</title>
      <link>/posts/pink-white-and-blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/pink-white-and-blue/</guid>
      <description>This office block in Sumida City caught my eye, the very man made colour framed by the pink, white and blue of nature.
It overlooks the Sumida River Park, a very pleasant long thin park whose pathways mark the boundary between many of the eastern and western districts of Sumida ward.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complex Road Junction</title>
      <link>/posts/complex-road-junction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/complex-road-junction/</guid>
      <description>Hakozaki Junction in Kakigaracho is typical of many such junctions in Tokyo. Multiple levels of overhead roads somehow weaving between hi-rise buildings, and barely noticeable from the streets below.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tokyo Station</title>
      <link>/posts/tokyo-station/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tokyo-station/</guid>
      <description>Tokyo Station is an immense building with an amazing history. Here is the south side of the station, and the central dome.
It sits astride a massively complex transit system nexus and a vast underground shopping mall. With trains and metros, taxis, busses and coaches it truely is a location where journeys begin, end and transition.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shibuya in the rain</title>
      <link>/posts/shibuya-in-the-rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/shibuya-in-the-rain/</guid>
      <description>The night time city is always aglow with its endless neon (or more likely LED) lights, but when it rains the streets are covered with rivers of reflected lights that are quite otherworldly. The Shibuya Scramble Crossing is always a special place to be, but at night in a quiet warm rain with my combini umbrella there are few other places I would rather be.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joyful Shopping Street</title>
      <link>/posts/joyful-shopping-street/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/joyful-shopping-street/</guid>
      <description>Whilst not necessarily “Joyful” as such, I always find it a joy to discover these covered shopping streets, or shotengai, that still cater for their local communities. There are numerous little stores selling all manner of produce and services. And above them are often the residences of the store owners. This one, actually called the Joyful Minowa Shopping Street, is in Minamisenju and my favourite way to get there is to take the Arakawa Tram to the terminus at Minowabashi.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Marunouchi</title>
      <link>/posts/towards-marunouchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/towards-marunouchi/</guid>
      <description>Around the Imperial Palace there is open space that allows you to step back a little from the tall, close set forest of concrete, metal and glass. This is a view up Gyoko Dori towards Tokyo Station and Marunouchi. The people lucky enough to work at or near one of those myriad windows must surely have a splendid view of the Palace grounds behind me.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giant Plush</title>
      <link>/posts/giant-plush/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/giant-plush/</guid>
      <description>There is one thing you can be sure of in Tokyo, and that is that you do not have to go far before something stops you in your tracks as you try to figure out the what and the why of it. This is one such item I came across deep inside Tokyo Station. I can only assume people used to walk into the pillar it surrounds.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinshi Park</title>
      <link>/posts/kinchi-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/kinchi-park/</guid>
      <description>Kinshi Park is a well maintained and interesting park area with a wide avenue of cherry trees running across it. The clocks and the childrens activity area especially caught my eye, but there are lots of unusual little things, like the tap, and the small, rounded, open sided cubes seen here.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colourful Play Park</title>
      <link>/posts/colourful-play-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/colourful-play-park/</guid>
      <description>There are countless play areas for kids in Tokyo and often they appear in the most unusual locations. This one, however, is in a corner of the larger Kinshi Park in Sumida City. I love its bold bright colours and futuristic theme. Shame there were no children around to enjoy it that Tuesday morning.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sakura Waters</title>
      <link>/posts/sakura-waters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/sakura-waters/</guid>
      <description>There is something almost overwhelming about the quantity of all things sakura in Tokyo. How can the most urban of cities find room for so many cherry trees? How can each tree put forth so many flowers? How can you not be awed at blizzards of pink petals in the air around you, and carpets of pink at your feet and in the city waterways. Here are a few petals on some still waters in the Sumida River Park.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracks and Skytree</title>
      <link>/posts/tracks-and-skytree/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tracks-and-skytree/</guid>
      <description>The Skytree watches over vast tracts of Tokyo, much of which still has an older, smaller, more patinated atmosphere. Areas around train tracks especially have that feel. Looking across the Tobu-Kameido Line here in Oshiage is one such place. Though only taken a year or so back the red building opposite is now gone, soon to replaced with who knows what.
That is another constant in Tokyo: Change.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Living City</title>
      <link>/posts/living-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/living-city/</guid>
      <description>This photograph, looking over Minato city, shows in microcosm, the complexity of Tokyo. It does not take long, witnessing scenes like this, to feel that the city is a living entity.
Remember you can right click on the image to access it full size - something I especially recommend for photographs like this one.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hachiko</title>
      <link>/posts/hachiko/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hachiko/</guid>
      <description>The statue of the loyal dog, Hachiko, is probably the busiest meeting place in Tokyo. Outside Shibuya Station and next to the Scramble Crossing it is almost always heaving with locals waiting for friends and tourists posing for photos and touching his paw to ensure their wish to return to Tokyo is fulfilled.
This photograph was taken on a rare occasion when the area was fenced off for a ceremony.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ningyocho Street Clock</title>
      <link>/posts/ningyocho-street-clock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ningyocho-street-clock/</guid>
      <description>Almost all of the wards and districts I have visited in Tokyo have a strong sense of their history and uniqueness in their shops, buildings and public art. This street clock is a good example of the many ways this uniqueness and character manifests itself in everyday life.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycles and alleyways</title>
      <link>/posts/bicycles-and-alleyways/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/bicycles-and-alleyways/</guid>
      <description>There often seem to be a huge number of cyclists on the paths of Tokyo, and this is reflected by their many mounts seen against railings, on rooftops and, as here, lining narrow alleyways.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wall Tiles</title>
      <link>/posts/wall-tiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/wall-tiles/</guid>
      <description>One of the more fascinating details of traditional Japanese buildings are their roof tiles. Often they are too high to get up close and really see the detail, but here, topping a section of wide wall around the Zojoji temple grounds near the Tokyo Tower, they are low enough to touch.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rainbow Candyfloss</title>
      <link>/posts/rainbow-candyfloss/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/rainbow-candyfloss/</guid>
      <description>There are countless businesses producing a myriad products I just cannot see being viable anywhere othere than Tokyo. Long may they all thrive.
This Totti Candy Factory Rainbow Candyfloss is one such product many enjoy on Takeshita Dori in Harajuku.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tree and Skytree</title>
      <link>/posts/tree-and-skytree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tree-and-skytree/</guid>
      <description>The Tokyo Skytree is visible for much of the length of the long and thin Sumida River Park. A very pleasant park on a cool spring morning.
At this point the east (right hand) half of the park is in Kotobashi and the west side is in Midori. You can weave in and out of a dozen different districts as you walk along its winding paths.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
