<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>public art on Tokyo, endless city</title>
    <link>/tags/public-art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in public art on Tokyo, endless city</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/tags/public-art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cute Door</title>
      <link>/posts/cute_door/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/cute_door/</guid>
      <description>I am not enamoured of all things kawaii, but there is something intriguing about a door like this. One has to wonder what lies behind. Perhaps I have been watching too many Ghibli movies. This door was beside the Sumikko Gurashi store along 1st Avenue in the underground shopping mall of Tokyo Station on the Yaesu side.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giant Plush</title>
      <link>/posts/giant-plush/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/giant-plush/</guid>
      <description>There is one thing you can be sure of in Tokyo, and that is that you do not have to go far before something stops you in your tracks as you try to figure out the what and the why of it. This is one such item I came across deep inside Tokyo Station. I can only assume people used to walk into the pillar it surrounds.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hachiko</title>
      <link>/posts/hachiko/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hachiko/</guid>
      <description>The statue of the loyal dog, Hachiko, is probably the busiest meeting place in Tokyo. Outside Shibuya Station and next to the Scramble Crossing it is almost always heaving with locals waiting for friends and tourists posing for photos and touching his paw to ensure their wish to return to Tokyo is fulfilled.
This photograph was taken on a rare occasion when the area was fenced off for a ceremony.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancers in the park</title>
      <link>/posts/dancers-in-the-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/dancers-in-the-park/</guid>
      <description>Tokyo has a wonderful array of public art, from tiny utility hole covers to, well, Godzilla sized pieces.
I came across this slender and graceful piece in the small Hamachō park beside the Sumida river during Hanami season.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ningyocho Street Clock</title>
      <link>/posts/ningyocho-street-clock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ningyocho-street-clock/</guid>
      <description>Almost all of the wards and districts I have visited in Tokyo have a strong sense of their history and uniqueness in their shops, buildings and public art. This street clock is a good example of the many ways this uniqueness and character manifests itself in everyday life.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
