<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>chuo on Tokyo, endless city</title>
    <link>/tags/chuo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chuo on Tokyo, endless city</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/tags/chuo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ningyocho Night Bars</title>
      <link>/posts/ningyocho-nighttime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ningyocho-nighttime/</guid>
      <description>There is something wonderful about the bright neon lights and other signs that beckon you into darkened doorways on streets all around Tokyo. They often appear intimidating, especially for those without any Japanses language skills, but I have never had a bad experience and always found both the staff and clientel to be welcoming and friendly. This is a short stretch of a small street in Ningyocho.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roads and Skylines</title>
      <link>/posts/roads-and-skylines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/roads-and-skylines/</guid>
      <description>This photograph was taken looking south towards Shinkawa towards the end of the day. The red brickwork is part of the Royal Park Hotel.
I love the way layer upon layer of high rise buildings jostle for a place in the sky, presenting a line far more complex than the most intricate key, and just as unique. From every one of countless windows there is a different and individual skyline.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Royal Park Hotel</title>
      <link>/posts/royal-park-hotel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/royal-park-hotel/</guid>
      <description>The Royal Park Hotel in Nihonbashi Kakigara-cho, close to Suitengumae metro station, has an impressive red brick appeal and a fascinating tower rising along the outside corner of the L shaped building. The circular windows in the rooms afford 270 degree views over the north and east and an envieable view of Tokyo Tower. Well worth a stay if you can afford it.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roads upon roads upon roads upon roads</title>
      <link>/posts/roads-upon-roads/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/roads-upon-roads/</guid>
      <description>The complexity of the transport infrastructure is not often appreciated from ground level, but at some places you can look up and see a glimpse of it. Like here at Hakozaki Junction where four layers of roads can be seen.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complex Road Junction</title>
      <link>/posts/complex-road-junction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/complex-road-junction/</guid>
      <description>Hakozaki Junction in Kakigaracho is typical of many such junctions in Tokyo. Multiple levels of overhead roads somehow weaving between hi-rise buildings, and barely noticeable from the streets below.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dawn over Nihonbashi Hakozaki-cho</title>
      <link>/posts/dawn-over-nihonbashihakozakicho/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/dawn-over-nihonbashihakozakicho/</guid>
      <description>There must be three dozen different buildings visible in this tiny sliver of Tokyo looking south west over Nihonbashi Hakozaki-cho. Each has its own architecture, scale and texture, standing on its own uniquely shaped plot of land. It was dawn on an April weekday when this was taken and most of these buildings were filling up with daily commuters as they began their working day.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancers in the park</title>
      <link>/posts/dancers-in-the-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/dancers-in-the-park/</guid>
      <description>Tokyo has a wonderful array of public art, from tiny utility hole covers to, well, Godzilla sized pieces.
I came across this slender and graceful piece in the small Hamachō park beside the Sumida river during Hanami season.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ningyocho Street Clock</title>
      <link>/posts/ningyocho-street-clock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ningyocho-street-clock/</guid>
      <description>Almost all of the wards and districts I have visited in Tokyo have a strong sense of their history and uniqueness in their shops, buildings and public art. This street clock is a good example of the many ways this uniqueness and character manifests itself in everyday life.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycles and alleyways</title>
      <link>/posts/bicycles-and-alleyways/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/bicycles-and-alleyways/</guid>
      <description>There often seem to be a huge number of cyclists on the paths of Tokyo, and this is reflected by their many mounts seen against railings, on rooftops and, as here, lining narrow alleyways.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
