<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>temple on Tokyo, endless city</title>
    <link>/tags/temple/</link>
    <description>Recent content in temple on Tokyo, endless city</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/tags/temple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hina Matsuri Dolls</title>
      <link>/posts/hinamatsuri-dolls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hinamatsuri-dolls/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m afraid I have forgotton exactly where I came across this display of Hina Matsuri dolls, other than that it was in a small temple somewhere in the North East of Tokyo. I have since read that these are displayed by families on Girls Day on the 3rd March each year to pray for the healthy growth of young girls. I believe that sometimes Temples take old, discarded dolls and display them for a while as a kind of memorial service for them before storing them away, or, in some cases burning them to release their spirits.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roof Tiles and Rain Chains</title>
      <link>/posts/roof-tiles-and-rain-chains/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/roof-tiles-and-rain-chains/</guid>
      <description>I love Japanese roof tiles. Their texture, shape, glaze and colours are a major contributor to the appeal of temples and other traditional Japanese buildings. Another fascinating element of such buildings are the rain chains, or kusari-doi, that so much more elegantly deal with off-roof water flow than the usual drainpipe.
This photograph is of part of the Jyokan-ji temple near Minowa Station. It lies right on the boundary of the Arakawa and Tatio wards which is a fascinating area to explore</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jōkan-ji Door</title>
      <link>/posts/jokan-ji-door/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/jokan-ji-door/</guid>
      <description>Around the back of the Jōkan-ji temple is a door behind which are stored the remains of a great many women whose sad story is well worth looking into.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
